Finding Aid for Alvin M. Bentley Papers 1935-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio-Visual Materials
  Audio-Visual (1.3 linear ft.; 1950s-1960s, scattered) includes photographs, motion picture film, and sound recordings. Of special note are photos from Bentley's various political campaigns and a film (silent but including a script) of a program with David Brinkley relating to the aftermath of the shooting in the U.S. House of Representatives.
  - Photographs
    - Alma College building dedication 1954 (Box 103)
    - Assembly of Captive European Nations-Plenary meeting June 28, 1957 (Box 103)
    - Bentley, Alvin M.
      - Portraits (Box 103)
        (include Mrs. Bentley; also Christmas and with family)
      - Last photos (Box 103)
    - Campaigns
      - 1952-1956 (Box 103)
      - 1958 (Box 103)
      - 1960
        - General (Box 103)
        - Muskegon (include Nixon photos), 2 folders (Box 103)
      - 1962
        - General (Box 103)
        - Detroit Campaign headquarters open house (Box 103)
        - With elephants (Box 103)
      - 1964
    - Civilian Defense Shelters (Box 103)
    - Colleagues (Box 103)
    - Colleague-signed photos (Box 103)
    - Conventions (Box 103)
    - Ethnic groups (Box 103)
    - Family (Box 103)
    - Foreign Affairs Committee (Box 103)
    - Friends, constituents (Box 103)
    - Groups-high school and scouts (Box 103)
    - Groups-identified (Box 103)
    - Groups-unidentified (Box 103)
    - Individuals (Box 103)
    - Michigan subjects (Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 103)
    - Presidents (Box 103)
    - Project HOPE (Box 103)
    - Public appearances
      - Dated (Box 103)
      - Undated (Box 103)
      - Parades and festivals (Box 103)
    - Republican candidates 1962 (Box 103)
    - Saginaw Valley flood 1956 (Box 103)
    - Shooting the House of Representatives and related subjects (Box 103)
    - Shooting in the House (script for David Brinkley TV broadcast) (Box 103)
    - Travel (Box 103)
    - Travel-Puerto Rico (Box 103)
    - Veterans (Box 103)
    - Album given to AMB by Puerto Rican school children, 1 volumes (Box 103)
    - Oversize photographs (Box 104)
  - Motion Pictures
    (16 mm, silent; use copies on U-Matic videocassette)
    - Bentley family at home during winter (in color) (Box 103)
    - NBC report with David Brinkley of aftermath of shooting in House of Representatives March 1, 1954 (B&W, no sound track; script available) (Box 103)
  - Sound recordings
    - Unprocessed (Box 103)